Before getting into the definition of valuables, let us relate them to an old mathematical equation.
Many of us would have solved many mathematical equations since childhood.
As an example, consider the function here and that equation x squared plus y minus two equal to one.
The important thing that we need to understand that the equation has names X and Y, which hold values
or date.
So X would hold data or value and Y in the same way.
That means names X and Y are place holders for representing the date.
Similarly, in computer science programming, we need something for all linked data and variables in
there.
The way to do that, we have to create a valuable X and we have to create a variable Y in order to hold
the deck.
In this equation, the variable X and Y can take any values, such as integral numbers 10 or 20 real
numbers as high as zero point four, thirty six point three or just zero or one in the same way.
Why could take the 53 or nine or zero point two one one or eight point seven or zero or one?
OK.
To solve the equation, we need to relate them to kind of values.
They can take and data type is the name used in computer science programming for this purpose.
That data type in the programming language is a set of data with predefined values.
Examples of data types are integer like then 20.
Float as zero point four, three or six point three.
And Boolean zero or one.
OK, computer memory is all filled with zeros and ones.
If we have a problem and we want to code it, it's very difficult to provide the solution in terms of
zeros and one to help users.
Programming languages and compilers provide us with data types.
So, for example, we have integer, we have float integer stake.
It takes two bytes.
Actually, actual value depends on compiler and float takes four bytes and etc..
This says that in memory, we are combining two bytes or 16 bits and calling it an integer OK for that
purpose.
We have a data type reduces decoding effort at the top level.
There are two types of data types that primitive data, which are integer float or Boolean and another
type is called user defined data types such as objects.
OK, so data types are primitive data like integer float or Boolean, and the user defined that we are
going to see later on.
OK, so the perimeter of the system data, our system defined data types like primitive data are like
int float ga double Boolean in like in Java A. and Python.
The number of bit allocated for each primitive data depends on the programming language and the compiler
and the operating system.
OK.
And it may differ for the dangers, for every type, why of the user defined data types.
If the system defined data types are not enough, then most programming languages allow the user to
define their own data types called user defined data types such as object.
Good example of user defined data types are structured in C or C++ and classes in Java.
We will see them later on in there through the.